Guide to the Arthur F. Burns Papers, 1911-2005 and undated, bulk 1940-1987 RL.00179
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1911-1997 and undated, bulk 1940-1987, 5 boxes; 347 electronic files
  - Correspondence by Individual, 1911-1985, bulk 1953-1981
    - Dwight David Eisenhower, 1953-1968 and undated, 17 folders
      - From Eisenhower to Burns, 1953-1968, 182 letters
        - 1956 Aug. 18 (Box 1)
          Re: Economic tables created by Burns.
        - 1956 Oct. 22 (Box 1)
        - 1956 Nov. 10 (Box 1)
        - 1956 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns's resignation from public service.
        - 1956 Nov. 28 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns's note on the chairmanship of the Cabinet Committee on Small Business and Dr. Saulnier's appointment as the chairman.
        - 1956 Dec. 5 (Box 1)
        - 1956 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
        - 1957 Jan. 2 (Box 1)
        - 1957 Jan. 3 (Box 1)
          Re: Tax deductions.
        - 1957 Mar. 28 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns's statement on lowering government expenditures.
        - 1957 Apr. 24 (Box 1)
        - 1957 May 2 (Box 1)
          From Bernard M. Shanley.
        - 1957 May 16 (Box 1)
        - 1957 June 1 (Box 1)
          Re: Political support for the budget.
        - 1957 June 15 (Box 1)
          Re: A misunderstanding between Eisenhower and Burns.
        - 1957 June 24 (Box 1)
          Re: Fighting inflation.
        - 1957 Oct. 12 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns's note on stock market activities.
        - 1957 Nov. 4 (Box 1)
        - 1957 Nov. 16 (Box 1)
        - 1957 Nov. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1957 Dec. 4 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Jan. 4 (Box 1)
          Re: Difficulties encountered by the members of the American Economic Association in inviting two Russians to present papers at the association's convention.
        - 1958 Jan. 10 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Jan. 21 (Box 1)
          From Sherman Adams.
        - 1958 Jan. 28 (Box 1)
          From Robert Cutler. Attached: Memo regarding Mar. 3 meeting.
        - 1958 Feb. 3 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Feb. 7 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Feb. 12 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Feb. 24 [Personal] (Box 1)
          Re: Request that Burns write a letter to Time Magazine against the opposition's critiques regarding the recession.
        - 1958 Mar. 4 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Mar. 12 [Personal] (Box 1)
        - 1958 Mar. 20 [Personal] (Box 1)
          Re: Opinions and expectations regarding the recession.
        - 1958 Mar. 24 (Box 1)
          Re: Tax deduction.
        - 1958 Apr. 2 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns's suggestions on a plan required for stimulating economic recovery.
        - 1958 Apr. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Apr. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Apr. 28 (Box 1)
        - 1958 May 7 [Personal] (Box 1)
          Re: Tax reduction.
        - 1958 May 8 (Box 1)
        - 1958 May 15 [Personal] (Box 1)
        - 1958 June 6 (Box 1)
          Re: Political support for tax reform.
        - 1958 June 18 (Box 1)
        - 1958 June 19 (Box 1)
          From Assistant to the President.
        - 1958 Aug. 23 (Box 1)
          Re: Gratitude for Burns's support for the Department of Defense Reorganization Plan..
        - 1958 Sept. 29 (Box 1)
          Re: Economic matters in the election campaign and governmental expenditures. Attached: Letter from Ezra Benson to Eisenhower, 1958 Sept. 26, regarding inflationary tendencies and budget deficit. Contains 2 copies of attached letter.
        - 1958 Sept. 30 (Box 1)
          From Eisenhower's assistant to Burns regarding disagreement between Burns and Eisenhower on economic matters.
        - 1958 Oct. 7 (Box 1)
          Eisenhower's comments on non-cooperation of unions.
        - 1958 Oct. 27 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Nov. 3 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Nov. 21 (Box 1)
          From Gabriel Hague.
        - 1958 Nov. 24 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Nov. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1958 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns' suggestions on the budget and encouraging individual initiatives.
        - 1959 Feb. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1959 Mar. 11 (Box 1)
          Re: National Unemployment Insurance and state relations with the federal government.
        - 1959 Apr. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1959 Oct. 29 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns' conversation with a Russian economist about the United States' transition to a lower level of defense spending.
        - 1959 June 19 (Box 1)
          From Robert E. Merriam.
        - 1959 Dec. 29 (Box 1)
        - 1960 Mar. 17 (Box 1)
          Re: 1960 election.
        - 1960 Apr. 2 (Box 1)
        - 1960 May 16 (Box 1)
          From Eisenhower's Deputy Assistant Bryce N. Harlow to Burns. Attached: Message dictated by Eisenhower to his Deputy Assistant and sent without signature to Burns because of urgency, 1960 May 14. Eisenhower states concerns about how a possible hindrance regarding the budget allowed to the "Mutual Security Program" would threaten defense alliance structures such as NATO and SEASO.
        - 1960 May 23 (Box 1)
        - 1960 June 8 (Box 1)
        - 1960 June 9 (Box 1)
        - 1960 Aug. 1 (Box 1)
        - 1960 Sept. 6 (Box 1)
        - 1960 Nov. 5 (Box 1)
        - 1960 Dec. 26 (Box 1)
        - 1961 May 11 (Box 1)
          Re: Gold reserve policy and the Cuban fiasco.
        - 1961 May 26 (Box 1)
        - 1961 June 7 (Box 1)
        - 1961 June 14 (Box 1)
        - 1961 June 14 (Box 1)
          Re: Mrs. Luce's public letter about the Cuban failure.
        - 1961 June 23 (Box 1)
        - 1961 July 15 (Box 1)
        - 1961 Aug. 11 (Box 1)
          From Eisenhower's secretary, Ann Whitman, to Burns. Attached: 2 items. Letter from Eisenhower to Felix Edgar Wormser, 1961 Aug. 10. Letter from Wormser to Eisenhower, 1961 Aug. 8, regarding the gold crisis.
        - 1961 Aug. 15 (Box 1)
        - 1961 Aug. 28 (Box 1)
          From Eisenhower's secretary, Ann Whitman, to Burns.
        - 1961 Sept. 18 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns' letter to Mr. Nehru.
        - 1961 Oct. 21 (Box 1)
          Re: Republican Party's financial troubles.
        - 1961 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
        - 1961 Dec. 15 (Box 1)
        - 1962 Jan. 30 (Box 1)
          Re: Organizing shadow cabinet in every state controlled by Democrats.
        - 1962 Feb. 4 (Box 1)
          Attached: 4 items. Cover note from Eisenhower's secretary, Ann Whitman, to Burns. Letter from Eisenhower to Burns, undated. Letter from Eisenhower to Andrew Baldwin. Letter from Baldwin to Eisenhower, 1962 Dec. 30, regarding plan to stabilize American industry.
        - 1962 Apr. 12 (Box 1)
        - 1962 Apr. 20 (Box 1)
        - 1962 June 30 (Box 1)
        - 1962 July 11 (Box 1)
        - 1962 July 16 (Box 1)
        - 1962 Nov. 30 (Box 1)
          Re: The first volume of Eisenhower's memoirs.
        - 1963 Jan. 24 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Feb. 8 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Feb. 17 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Mar. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Apr. 17 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Apr. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1963 Dec. 27 (Box 1)
          Re: Eisenhower's donation of his personal papers to the Eisenhower Library at Abilene and his request to Burns to donate his related personal papers to the same institution.
        - 1964 Jan. 17 (Box 1)
          Re: Burns' decision to donate some of his personal papers to the Eisenhower Library at Abilene.
        - 1964 Mar. 6 (Box 1)
        - 1964 Apr. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1964 May 15 (Box 1)
        - 1964 July 29 (Box 1)
        - 1964 Aug. 21 (Box 1)
          Attached: 2 items. Excerpt from Jacques Rueff's book The Age of Inflation. Bulletin #503, Dollar Erosion by M. Polyi. Contains copies of both items.
        - 1964 Aug. 28 (Box 1)
        - 1964 Oct. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1964 Nov. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1964 Dec. 15 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Feb. 12 (Box 1)
          Attached: 2 items. Letter from Eisenhower to Walter Spahr, 1965 Feb. 12. Letter from Rusty Brown to Burns, 1965 Feb. 12.
        - 1965 Mar. 13 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Mar. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Apr. 9 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Apr. 27 (Box 1)
        - 1965 May 6 (Box 1)
        - 1965 May 12 (Box 1)
          Re: Eisenhower's view that historians would have a more favorable view on the economy policies of the 1950s than the 1960s.
        - 1965 Oct. 5 (Box 1)
          Attached: Paper presentation by unidentified author, undated, regarding the problems of development in developing countries.
        - 1965 Oct. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Oct. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Nov. 21 (Box 1)
        - 1965 Dec. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Jan. 18 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Jan. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Feb. 22 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Feb. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Mar. 12 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Apr. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1966 June 22 (Box 1)
          Re: Vietnam.
        - 1966 Aug. 10 (Box 1)
        - 1966 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
          Attached: Article by W. L. White, Why We Must Stop Inflation, undated.
        - 1966 Dec. 5 (Box 1)
          Attached: 4 items. News clippings, De Gaulle's Red Face, Philadelphia Inquirer, 1966 Dec. 5; Amisted Dam-a Reminder, Philadelphia Inquirer, 1966 Dec. 5; Unbridled Insurrection at Berkeley, Philadelphia Inquirer, 1966 Dec. 5.
        - 1966 Dec. 8 (Box 1)
          Attached: Article by R. C. McCormic, Pill Drill, undated.
        - 1966 Dec. 9 (Box 1)
          Re: The Vietnam War and population growth.
        - 1966 Dec. 14 (Box 1)
          Telegram.
        - 1967 Jan. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1967 Apr. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1967 May 22 (Box 1)
        - 1967 May 31 (Box 1)
        - 1967 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
        - 1967 Nov. 24 (Box 1)
          Re: Eisenhower's comments on Burns' attached speech draft. Attached: Draft of Burns' speech, The Defense Sector: An Evaluation of its Economic and Social Impact, with handwritten notes and comments by Eisenhower, 1967 Nov. 17.
        - 1967 Dec. 7 (Box 1)
          From Brigadier General Robert L. Schulz, Executive Assistant to Eisenhower, to Burns.
        - 1968 Jan. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1968 Feb. 8 (Box 1)
          Attached: 3 items. Letter from Eisenhower to Maurice Feldman, 1968 Feb. 8. Letter from Feldman to Eisenhower, 1968 Jan. 29. News clipping: Eisenhower's Views on Travel Curbs, 1968 Jan. 28
        - 1968 Apr. 24 (Box 1)
        - 1968 May 8 (Box 1)
        - 1968 Oct. 17 (Box 1)
      - From Burns to Eisenhower, 1954-1955, 24 letters
        - 1954 Jan. 13 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Feb. 1 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Feb. 5 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Feb. 8 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Mar. 9 (Box 1)
          Re: Unemployment figures.
        - 1954 Mar. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Apr. 16 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Apr. 29 (Box 1)
        - 1954 May 26 (Box 1)
        - 1954 July 19 (Box 1)
          To Sherman Adams.
        - 1954 Aug. 16 (Box 1)
          Re: 1955 budget.
        - 1954 Aug. 17 (Box 1)
          To Sherman Adams. Re: Kuykendall letter, private investment in power.
        - 1954 Aug. 18 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Oct. 19 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
        - 1954 Dec. 24 (Box 1)
          Re: Increase in minimum wage.
        - 1954 Dec. 28 (Box 1)
        - 1955 Jan. 11 (Box 1)
        - 1955 Jan. 21 (Box 1)
          Re: Report of Cabinet Commission on Energy Supplies and Resource Policy.
        - 1955 Apr. 25 (Box 1)
        - 1955 Apr. 26 (Box 1)
        - 1955 May 24 (Box 1)
          To Sherman Adams. Re: Aircraft industry decline.
        - 1955 Aug. 18 (Box 1)
          Re: August budget message. Attached: Historical table of political control.
        - 1955 Sept. 30 (Box 1)
          To Major General Howard McSnyder.
    - Mamie Doud Eisenhower, 1955-1971, 2 folders
      Mamie Eisenhower's correspondence with Burns consists of notes of greeting, thanks, and condolence.
      - Mamie Eisenhower to Burns, 3 letters
        - 1955 Sept. 28 (Box 1)
        - 1966 July 6 (Box 1)
        - 1971 Dec. 15 (Box 1)
      - Burns to Mamie Eisenhower, 1 letter
        - 1969 Apr. 1 (Box 1)
          Re: Eisenhower's death.
    - Gerald Ford, 1974-1987, 3 folders
      Burns continued to be the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board during the Ford Administration. Ford's correspondence to Burns primarily consists of routine notes of appreciation for Burns's work, for having sent materials, for his comments on economic matters, and for his donation to the Ford Library. Also included are invitations, congratulations, and notes of regret. Burns's side of the correspondence expresses ideas regarding economic matters such as the ongoing recession, Federal Reserve policies, and the Financial Reform Act.
      - From Ford to Burns, 1974-1987, 22 letters
        - 1974 Aug. 9 (Box 1)
          Memo to agencies.
        - 1975 July 21 (Box 1)
        - 1976 Feb. 2 (Box 1)
        - 1976 Sept. 9 (Box 1)
        - 1976 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
        - 1977 Jan. 31 (Box 1)
        - 1977 Feb. 9 (Box 1)
        - 1977 Jun 17 (Box 1)
        - 1978 June 7 (Box 1)
        - 1978 July 11 (Box 1)
        - 1979 Jan. 2 (Box 1)
        - 1979 May 23 (Box 1)
        - 1980 Feb. 27 (Box 1)
        - 1981 May 22 (Box 1)
          Attached: Letter from Ford to Charles Percy in support of nomination of Burns as ambassador to Germany, 1981 May 22.
        - 1981 July 7 (Box 1)
        - 1982 Aug. 26 (Box 1)
        - 1984 July 20 (Box 1)
        - 1985 Feb. 5 (Box 1)
        - 1986 July 7 (Box 1)
        - 1987 Mar. 26 (Box 1)
        - 1987 Apr. 30 (Box 1)
        - 1987 May 21 (Box 1)
          Attached: Guest list for Gerald R. Ford Foundation's annual meeting in Washington, D.C. on June 10, 1987
      - From Burns to Ford, 1974-1982, 49 letters
        - 1974 Aug. 12 (Box 2)
          To Herbert Stein. Attached: Memo for President re: Economic agenda.
        - 1974 Aug. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Aug. 27 (Box 2)
          Memo re: Expanded public service program.
        - 1974 Sept. 25 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Oct. 8 (Box 2)
          Address of President to Joint Session of Congress.
        - 1974 Oct. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Oct. 16 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Nov. 27 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Dec. 6 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Jan. 30 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Feb. 7 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Mar. 2 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Mar. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Mar. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Mar. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Apr. 16 (Box 2)
          Attached: CV of Philip C. Jackson Jr.
        - 1975 May 1 (Box 2)
        - 1975 May 7 (Box 2)
        - 1975 June 3 (Box 2)
          Confidential memo.
        - 1975 July 14 (Box 2)
        - 1975 July 25 (Box 2)
        - 1975 July 30 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Aug. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Sept. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Sept. 26 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Oct. 8 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Oct. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Oct. 24 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Nov. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Nov. 13 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Dec. 12 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Jan. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Jan. 26 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Feb. 4 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Feb. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Mar. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Mar. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Apr. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1976 May 3 (Box 2)
        - 1976 July 28 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Sept. 28 (Box 2)
          Attached: Letter from Ford to Burns, 1976 Sept. 23.
        - 1976 Nov. 12 (Box 2)
        - 1976 Nov. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1977 Jan. 17 (Box 2)
          Attached: News clipping.
        - 1977 Jan. 24 (Box 2)
        - 1977 May 27 (Box 2)
        - 1977 June 8 (Box 2)
        - 1977 Nov. 16 (Box 2)
        - 1982 Sept. 28 (Box 2)
    - Milton Friedman, 1940-1969 and undated, 3 folders
      Contains correspondence with renowned economist Milton Friedman that addresses theoretical debates, reactions to other economists' publications, academic posts and publishing, politics, personal matters, and critique and evaluation of each other's work.
      - From Friedman to Burns, 1940-1969 and undated, 28 letters
        - 1940 Sept. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1940 Nov. 17 (Box 2)
        - 1941 Mar. 2 (Box 2)
        - 1941 May 29 (Box 2)
        - 1941 Oct. 30 (Box 2)
          From Frank Knight to Friedman with Friedman's handwritten note to Burns.
        - 1942 Jan. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1942 July 21 (Box 2)
        - 1942 Sept. 23 (Box 2)
        - 1945 Oct. 30 (Box 2)
        - 1945 Dec. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1946 Feb. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1946 Feb. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1946 Mar. 3 (Box 2)
        - 1946 May 7 (Box 2)
        - 1946 Aug. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1948 Aug. 23 (Box 2)
          From Murray N. Rothbard to Burns with Friedman's handwritten note to Burns. Attached: Professor Nagel's reply to institutionalist criticism of economic theory.
        - 1949 Apr. 12 (Box 2)
        - 1951 Feb. 1 (Box 2)
        - 1951 Oct. 26 (Box 2)
        - 1954 Oct. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1958 Nov. 4 (Box 2)
        - 1959 Feb. 19 (Box 2)
          Attached: 1959 Feb. 19 Friedman letter to Al.
        - 1963 July 3 (Box 2)
        - 1969 Jan. 29 (Box 2)
          From Friedman to William McChesney Martin with Friedman's handwritten note to Burns.
        - Undated, Sunday [c. 1963] (Box 2)
        - Undated, Thursday [c. 1937-1940] (Box 2)
        - Undated, Thursday (Box 2)
        - Undated, Friday (Box 2)
      - From Burns to Friedman, 1954-1955 and undated, 6 letters
        - 1954 Oct. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1955 Feb. 25 (Box 2)
        - 1955 Apr. 26 (Box 2)
        - 1955 May 27 (Box 2)
        - 1955 Sept. 29 (Box 2)
        - Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander M. Haig, Jr., 1981-1984, 7 letters
      Haig's correspondence to Burns consists of routine notes expressing thanks for Burns's support and for having sent materials.
      - 1981 Sept. 30 (Box 2)
      - 1982 Mar. 8 (Box 2)
      - 1982 Nov. 1 (Box 2)
      - 1982 Dec. 30 (Box 2)
      - 1983 Mar. 28 (Box 2)
      - 1983 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
      - 1984 Jan. 20 (Box 2)
    - Hubert Humphrey, 1972-1977, 2 letters
      Humphrey's letters to Burns are notes of thanks for condolences after electoral defeat and for attending a reception.
      - 1972 July 26 (Box 2)
      - 1977 Jan. 23 (Box 2)
    - Lyndon Baines Johnson, 1963-1966, 2 folders
      In the letters, the President expresses his gratitude for Burns' advice regarding economic issues and for backing the administration's policies in Vietnam. Mr. Burns' activities as a Member of the President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy and his resignation from the committee in April 1966 are also addressed in the correspondence.
      - From Johnson to Burns, 1963-1966, 5 letters
        - 1963 Dec. 2 (Box 2)
        - 1964 Sept. 7 (Box 2)
        - 1965 Apr. 1 (Box 2)
        - 1966 Apr. 21 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns' resignation from the President's Advisory Committee on Labor Management Policy.
        - 1966 Dec. 7 (Box 2)
          .
      - From Burns to Johnson, 1964, 1 letter
        - 1964 Aug. 25 (Box 2)
    - John Fitzgerald Kennedy, 1961-1963, 4 letters
      Kennedy's correspondence to Burns consists of routine notes of thanks for sending information on economic problems and for serving on the Labor-Management Committee.
      - 1961 Mar. 7 (Box 2)
      - 1961 June 23 (Box 2)
      - 1961 June 29 (Box 2)
      - 1963 Feb. 7 (Box 2)
    - Henry Kissinger, 1982-1986, 4 letters
      Kissinger's correspondence to Burns consists of routine notes expressing thanks for Burns's support and for having sent materials.
      - 1982 Sept. 21 (Box 2)
      - 1984 Jan. 9 (Box 2)
      - 1986 May 30 (Box 2)
      - 1986 Aug. 14 (Box 2)
    - Helmut Kohl, 1982-1987, 8 letters
      Kohl's correspondence to Burns is entirely in German.
      - 1982 Dec. 17 (Box 2)
      - 1982 Dec. 20 (Box 2)
        Re: Letter from Burns to Kohl
      - 1982 Dec. 28 (Box 2)
      - 1983 Mar. 16 (Box 2)
      - 1983 Dec. 13 (Box 2)
      - 1984 May 7 (Box 2)
      - 1986 Jan. 31 (Box 2)
      - 1987 Jan. 21 (Box 2)
    - Teddy Kollek, 1985, 4 letters
      Kollek's correspondence to Burns concerns Burns' potential visit to Jerusalem and his help with rampant inflation in Israel.
      - 1985 June 24 (Box 2)
      - 19485 July 29 (Box 2)
        Re: Letter from Burns' secretary to Kollek.
      - 1985 Aug. 9 (Box 2)
        Re: Letter from Burns to Kollek.
      - 1985 Aug. 28 (Box 2)
    - Simon Kuznets, 1942-1945, 4 letters
      Kuznet's correspondence to Burns discusses the work of Frank Knight and Albert Wohlstetter on the War Production Board. Topics covered include the analysis of World War I output, the analysis of business cycles, and work on national income problems.
      - 1942 July 21 (Box 2)
      - 1942 Aug. 13 (Box 2)
      - 1943 Oct. 30 (Box 2)
      - 1945 June 4 (Box 2)
    - Robert C. McFarlane, 1985-1987, 3 letters
      McFarlane's correspondence to Burns consists of routine notes expressing thanks and a reserved optimism concerning the European economy.
      - 1985 June 28 (Box 2)
      - 1986 Aug. 7 (Box 2)
      - 1987 Mar. 11 (Box 2)
    - Edwin Meese III, 1981-1984, 4 letters
      McFarlane's correspondence to Burns consists of routine notes expressing thanks for sending materials.
      - 1981 Dec. 21 (Box 2)
      - 1982 Dec. 3 (Box 2)
      - 1983 Feb. 17 (Box 2)
      - 1984 May 23 (Box 2)
    - Wesley Clair Mitchell, 1911-1963, 2 folders
      Contains correspondence with Mitchell, an American economist famous for his empirical work on business cycles and for leading the NBER in its first decades, and his wife, Lucy Sprague Mitchell. Great attention is paid by Burns and Mitchell to revising each other's drafts and economic theories. Also included are articles by Mitchell, his obituary, eulogies, and correspondence regarding the dedication of a collection in his honor. Other letters authored by Mitchell can be found in the academic career and National Bureau of Economic Research folders - both in the Correspondence by Topic Subseries.
      - 1911 Oct. 18 (Box 2)
        Autobiographical letter
      - 1914 Nov. (Box 2)
        Reprint of Mitchell's essay Human Behavior and Economics: A Survey of Recent Literature from The Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol. XXIX
      - 1920 June 3 (Box 2)
      - 1929 June 5 (Box 2)
      - 1929 June 24 (Box 2)
      - 1929 July 22 (Box 2)
      - 1929 Aug. 19 (Box 2)
      - 1929 Dec. 19 (Box 2)
      - 1942 July 15 (Box 2)
      - 1942 Aug. 20 (Box 2)
      - 1945 Aug. 27 (Box 2)
        Discussion of Milton Friedman's theories
      - 1946 (Box 2)
        Mitchell's hand-edited copy of the Preface to Measuring Business Cycles, in which Burns and Mitchell propose a statistic-based definition of business cycles
      - 1948 (Box 2)
        Biographical memoir about Mitchell written by Burns in the Year Book of the American Philosophical Society, p. 280-285
      - 1948 (Box 2)
        Eulogy of Mitchell by Burns
      - 1948 (Box 2)
        Mitchell's obituary
      - 1948 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
        Lucy Sprague Mitchell to Burns
      - 1949 Feb. 22 (Box 2)
      - 1957 Feb. 22 (Box 2)
      - 1958 Oct. 28 (Box 2)
      - 1962 Nov. 9 (Box 2)
        Booklet from the dedication of the Wesley Clair Mitchell Collection in the Bank Street College of Education library
      - 1963 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
        John H. Niemeyer to Burns concerning the dedication of the Wesley Clair Mitchell Collection
    - Richard Milhous Nixon, 1955-1980, 12 folders
      Arthur Burns was the economic advisor to Nixon's 1968 presidential campaign and acted as Counselor to the President (1969) for a year after the election. He was appointed Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve in February 1970. The Nixon-Burns correspondence sheds light on the controversial years of Nixon's presidency and illustrates disagreements within the government regarding monetary policy, Burns' resistance to the politicization of the Federal Reserve, and his complaints about the White House staff. Burns' personal journals, also part of this collection, provide important and complimentary insights to the issues addressed in the Burns-Nixon correspondence.